Wrege, Charles D. Papers 6012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Papers
2004
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6012
33.5 cubic feet
33.5 linear ft.
Records.
5758039
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 13, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5167: Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management 5618 P: Charles D. Wrege History of Management Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographs 6012m: Charles D. Wrege "Facts and Fallacies of Hawthorne" Doctoral Dissertation. 1961 6012 AV: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Audio-Visual Materials 6013 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives 6014: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents 6014 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs 6054: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Additional Taylor Charts 6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection 6271: Charles D. Wrege Collection of International Management Institute Correspondence 6304: Charles Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Index Cards
Wrege, Charles D.
5758039
- Gilbreth Data - Frank Gilbreth. Letter from Ernestine Gilbreth Carey (daughter); correspondence; files; patent information; photos of medical field experiments (from Smithsonian original glass plates. CDW paid $15 each, now in the 6012 P collection). (Box 1)
  - Gilbreth Materials from Jim Perkins, February 27, 1980 G (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Misc. papers
  - Frank Gilbreth, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Book and misc. papers
  - Gilbreth Photos at Cornell, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Photos
  - Gilbreth Dental Photos (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Gilbreth Surgery Photos Smithsonian File (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey Letters 1980, G E.G. Carey (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters with Leslie Gilbert (Gilbreth Brain Research) 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Gilbreth Obituary 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gilbreth - Efficiency and the High Brow, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - C. Daniel McClean on Gilbreth 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Keith Dowden - Purdue - Letters on Copying N-File of Gilbreth 1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Lillian Gilbreth Letter (Original) January 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey Correspondence - 1979 C (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Keith Dowden of Purdue on Gilbreth 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey - 1980-81, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - E.G. Carey Correspondence - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Envelope
  - Correspondence on Frank Gilbreth and Hospitals - Ernestine G. Carey 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ernestine Gilbreth Carey 10/21/83, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Misc. papers and envelope
  - Ernestine G. Carey 10/25/85 (M Gilbreth), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter from Ernestine Carey on Jan Perkins and Gilbreth Film 1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Dr. Paul Yakovlec, Myrtle Canavan Brain Slides 1983, Gilbreth Brain Study (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Albert Nock, American Magazine March 1913, "Efficiency and The High Brow," Gilbreth Data G (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Gilbreth "Micro-Motion Study" Scientific American Jan. 25, 1914, p. 84 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Copy
  - Efficiency Exhibition NYC April 4 to 11, 1914 Gilbreth (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Frank B. Gilbreth, "Scientific Management in the Hospital" The Modern Hospital 1914 Gilbreth (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "The Magic of Motion Study" The World's Work, July, 1916, pp. 321-336, Gilbreth and Meakeal Photos (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fatigue Study Gilbreth 1918 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Copy of Southard Letter on Gilbreth's 11/26/1919 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Gilbreth, Motion Study for the Handicapped 1920 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Peter Petersen - John's Hopkins 1985 (also Gilbreth Stop Watch Article 1921), 1921-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gilbreth - Nation's Health Nov. 1922 "A Teaching Device for Fatigue Elimination" (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gilbreth Articles G, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Edna Yost, Frank and Lillian Gilbreth: Partners for Life 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gilbreth Data from Yost Book G, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Time Out for Happiness F.B. Gilbreth, Jr., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Magazine
  - Margaret E. Hanley "The Life of Frank B. Gilbreth and His Contribution to the Science of Management" MA 1929 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    MA Thesis
  - Sanford Thompson Letter of 7/23/08 to Gilbreth, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Gilbreth - Taylor, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Taylor - Gilbreth Correspondence at Taylor Collection 4/21/66, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Note
  - Copy of Letter to F.B. Gilbreth 4/27/1908 to Thompson sent by Taylor (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Letter
  - Taylor to Thompson Dec. 9, 1907 on Gilbreth (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Taylor Letter to Thompson 4/6/08 on Gilbreth, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Taylor to Thompson 5/21/08 on Gilbreth, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Wanskuck Company and Gilbreth, 1981 (Correspondence with Ernestine Gilbreth Carey on her father) Gilbreth (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Letters
  - J.T. Black "I.E.'s Have Roots Too" Ind. Engineering May 1978, Vol 10, #5 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Article
  - Letter with Eleanor Pyne - Providence, R.I. - On New England Butt Co. and Gilbreth 1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - James H. Cashion Research Paper on John G. Aldrich and Gilbreth 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Gilbreth Photos at Cornell (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Copies of photos
  - George W. Dickerman (Developed Dental Devices for Frank Gilbreth), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Gilbreth Letters to Mary Jarrett Feb. 21, 1919, March 12, 1919, Gilbreth 1919, Mary Jarrett (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Letter Transparencies
  - Mary A Nutting (Friend of Gilbreth), 1939-1981 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Letters on Gilbreth Baseball Photos - 1980 G (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Brook Hammerle - Gilbreth Photos of Baseball Game in Providence R.I. 1913 (Letters to Hammerle 1990) (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hugo Munsterbeig Letters etc. at Boston Public Library on Gilbreth et al., 1905 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Article from Providence Newspaper of June 1913 on Early Gilbreth Photo Studies of Baseball Scenes, 1913-1990 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Letter and article
  - Richard Wolfe Letters 1980 on Moderne Man and Management (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Gilbreth Paper on Medical Sciences - 1981 Southwest Academy (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Health Care in America (on Gilbreth), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Search for "Factual Films" (e.g. Gilbreth Surgical Films) 1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Gilbreth Dental Photos, 1910-1918 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Misc. papers and copies of photos
  - Gilbreth and Dentistry, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Misc. papers and photos
  - Albert Nock, "Efficiency and The High Brow" on Gilbreth Surgery Studies, Gilbreth Medical Men, 1913 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Gilbreth Patent for Scaffold # 554, 024 - Feb. 4, 1896 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Research into Frank Gilbreth's Contractors Plant Company, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Frank B. Gilbreth - "Reinforced Concrete Dept" Reinforced Concrete at Yale and Towne Co. Illustration (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Original
  - Correspondence on Gilbreth with David Shayt, Smithsonian, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Search for Gilbreth Motion Models for David Shayt - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Gilbreth Material at Smithsonian, Gilbreth, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Gilbreth Material at Purdue and Smithsonian, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Smithsonian Index of Gilbreth Stereo Slide Collection, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Gilbreth Surgery Photos, Smithsonian File (Box 1, Folder 72)
    Copies of photos, originals
  - Anne W. Zurcher Letter - Re Gilbreth, Fall 1980 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Kate Pfordresher Health/PAC 1982 on Gilbreth Surgery photos (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - "Gilbreth's Lost Book" Ron Greenwood Letter 1982 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Cost Reducing By Intensive Management, Frank B. Gilbreth, 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Book
  - Some Aspects of Eliminating Waste in Teaching, Lillian Moller Gilbreth, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Binder
- Hawthorne Illumination Studies Background. Prior work, correspondence, articles, data CD Wrege gathered including some from the Edison National Historical Site in West Orange, NJ. Thomas Edison was Honorary Chairman of the Committee of Industrial Ligh (Box 2)
  - I.E.S., Illuminating Engineering, Vol. LI, #1, Jan. 1956 on Ind. Lighting (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Original article
  - Correspondence on "Better Light Better Sight" August 1959, 1925-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Original documents
  - Light Magazine March/April 1928 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Original magazine
  - Personal Research Federation 1929 Meeting on Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fred Wickert Letter on Hawthorne Studies Jan 14, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "What Made Gertrude Give" Factory, Management and Maintenance March 1951 (around p. 76), 1950-1951 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Originals and copies
  - Typed Copy "Discovering Hawthorne Roots", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Industrial Plant Illumination" George C. Keech, 1907 (Study at Hawthorne) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Original document
  - Correspondence on Present Day Gas Lighting and Hawthorne Studies 8/4/59, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Search for Gas Light Company Records in Michigan - 1959 (related to Hawthorne) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - J.L. Hudson Co. 1959 (use of barometric changes in Shoplifting relate to Huntington) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Henry Landsberger Correspondence 1958 on Hawthorne Studies (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Martha Elliot, Cooper-Hewitt Co., 1958 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Joseph Willis on Elton Mayo, Oct. 1957 to Willitts on Mayo (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Harold E. Burtt Correspondence on Intervale Avenue Tests of 1914 (File Under Intervale Lighting Tests), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Collection of Data from Illuminating Engineering Society Files - 1957 I.E.S. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Copies of "Good Lighting Advertisements" (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Originals
  - Correspondence with G.E. on "Better Light & Better Sight," Steinmet 1960 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Isolated Plant 1911 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1924 Johnson on Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Original letters
  - H. Richard Blackwell - Original copy of his data on better illumination at work 87 paper - plus photos and charts, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Original document, photos, and charts
  - Gas Lighting Data As Background for Hawthorne Studies 1959, EAS Lighting (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1981 - Data From Ron Greenwood on McGregor and Illumination, 1941-1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hess and Harrison, "Relation of Illumination to Production" 1923, Hawthorne Illumination Tests 1923 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    Copies
  - Data on Tungsten Lamp 1907 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Original booklet
  - Harry M. Johnson Illumination Studies 1924, Letter of 1959 (related to Hawthorne) (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Paper from The Edison Round Table Weekly, July 15, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Ward Harrison Patent 1, 374, 654, 4/12/1921 for RLM Reflector (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Directive Report, Haw. Illum. Tests (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Timken Roller Bearings Co. Tests 1923 (use for Work and Weather 1987) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Hen and Harmon Production at Timken Roller Bearings - Columbus, Ohio (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Data on Dover MSF. Co. (Presentation Hawthorne), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Travis, Kennedy, Mead, and Allphin "Muscle Action Potential as a Measure of Visual Performance, Illum. Engineering Vol. 46 No. 5 May 1951 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence with C. L. Crouch (Illuminating Engineering Society) on Dr. Blackwell's Studies in Visual Research - 9/3/58, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Business Development - Lighting Booklet - issued April 1922 (use for Hawthorne) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    Booklet
  - Correspondence with F.G. Montgomery 1963 on George Clewell's Work (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Ernest M. Patterson - Letter of 9/5/58 on Illumination and Prof. C.E. Clewell and Hawthorne, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Ernest Patterson 11/3/58 on Professor Clewell and Industrial Lighting, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Copies of Harold Burtt Correspondence with Hugo Munsterberg in 1914-1915 on Intervale Lighting Tests (from Boston Public Library) (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Copy of Harold Burtt Letter to Ron Greenwood 1982 (did street lighting study for Munsterberg in 1914) (Box 2, Folder 40)
    Copy of letter
  - Report to the National Electric Illuminating Society, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    Original reports
  - Photos of Intervale Ave. in the Bronx where NEIA Light Test Was Made in 1914 (1958) (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Envelope with original photos
  - Burtt Letters 1914 to Montgomery (Box 2, Folder 43)
    Copies of letters
  - Joint Meeting of Street Lighting Committees - April 7, 1914 (related to Intervale Avenue Tests - 1914 and Hawthorne), 1914-1959 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Edward K. Hall Data, 1930-1962 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Original documents and copies
  - Letter to Edmond Powers - on Street Lighting - July 14, 1959 Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Committee on Industrial Lighting Papers At Edison Laboratory 1957 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Hawthorne and Edison, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Copies of Letters
  - List of Documents on Committee of Industrial Lighting of National Research Council, at Edison Historic Site by CD Wrege 8/22/57, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - List of Members of Directive Board on NRC Committee of Ind. Lighting 10/21/24, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Edison Letter on CIL Meeting, 1924-1928 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    Photo and original document
  - Irving C. Whittemore Letters on Hawthorne - 11/6/57, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Jan 17, 1958 - Dr. Garner on Knight Dunlap and Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Thomas Edison Letter of 2/27/24 (accepting Honorary Chairman of Nat. Research Committee), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Edward K. Hall Research 1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Data on Change to Gray Bar Electric Co from Western Electric Supply Co. Jan 1, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    Copy of document
  - Correspondence with Jack Parsons on Dennison and Lynn Works, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Initial Search for Hawthorne Illumination Test Data 1957 Correspondence with J.W. Cooper, Oct 2 1957 of AT&T (life under snow) (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Dugald C. Jackson Letters on Committee of Industrial Lighting, 1927-1928 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    Copies of original documents
  - Inventory of Dugald Jackson papers - 1865-1951 MIT - 1982, 1865-1982 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    Slides
  - Elizabeth Andrews MIT Archives 12/1/94 on Dugald Jackson Papers for Hawthorne, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Originals and copies of documents
  - Dr. Kenneth Spence on Dr. Seashore and Dugald C. Jackson 1958 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence with Emily Osborne Dec 10, 1957 on Mayo (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Dr. Harold Pender - on Hawthorne and Dugald C. Jackson - Jan 7, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Letter to Gertrude Rand on Work for Dugald C. Jackson - 9/11/57, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - To James Olson, Lincoln, Nebraska on Dugald C. Jackson - July 14, 1959 and Alice Paine, Kearney, Nebraska 6/26/1959 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence with Miss Edna Blanchard on NRC Material at MIT 10/7/57, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Dugald C. Jackson & The Northern Electric Co. and Micro Fiche of his paper at MIT 1983 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Dugald C. Jackson to Pennock 2/23/27 (Copy), 1927 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Jackson to Pennock 2/23/27, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Jackson and Moreland Note on Illumination Tests 1927 (From MIT Archives) (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Copy of original
  - Paper 2 & 3 of Letter from D. Cozort on MIT Material on Individuals in Illumination Tests 11/18/77, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    Copies of originals
  - Data on Dugald C. Jackson to Check at Edison National Historic Site Files in West Orange, NJ 8/25/57 (added data Sept 4, 1979 on Jackson), 1957-1979 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Letter from Sam Hibben on 3/23/58 on Dugald Jackson, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Original letter
  - Vannevar Bush & NRC August 20, 1957 (Worked for Jackson at MIT) (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Dr. Atkins Search - 1958 (related to Jackson & Hawthorne) (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - R.G. Stansfield - London 2/17/1958 on Edward W. Atkins Study for Hawthorne and Steinwald, Johns Hopkins on Atkins - 3/7/58 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Ernest Atkins - did Illumination Tests at Johns Hopkins for MIT, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Willard Alphin - did 1925 glare test at MIT to study glare in 1924-1925 tests, Correspondence 1958 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Willard Alphin on "The Cost of Seeing a Critical Industrial Task" 1951 & in Illumination Engineering vol XLVI, #5, May 1951 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - George Geis - did thesis with Willard Alphin 1925 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Letter to James Osgood - Sylvanin - 1959 - on Lighting and Hawthorne 8/7/59 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - R.H. Brenneman (SDC) on Hawthorne 10/30/58, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - E.S. Prendergast - 1979 - on his work at Hawthorne (Box 2, Folder 84)
    Original correspondence
  - Prendergast Seminar Paper on Hawthorne 1931 (mentions Jarvis M. Wilson) (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - John A. Scott Letter 8/15/1957 (copy) - original in "original" file (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Jarvis B. Wilson - MIT (worked at Hawthorne 1929), 1985 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence with Dr. H.H. Wilson on Hawthorne 11-4-58, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Clark Elliot, Harvard, on Lenard Troland (made studies for Jackson) on Troland's death May 27, 1932, with Technicolor Co. 1925, 1932- 1979 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Leonard Troland Articles 1931, Joseph M Harrigan, for Committee on Industrial Lighting (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Glassteel Reflector Patent 1920's Ward. Harrison (use for Hawthorne Studies) 1958 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Copy of Al Bolton's Original Dissertation on Hawthorne 1981 (Box 2, Folder 92)
- National Research Council Test at Hawthorne (1924-1927). Supplements information already at Cornell including information on illumination tests, original output charts prepared by Charles E. Snow (principle investigator at Hawthorne, 1924- 1927). Cove (Box 3)
  - Andy Millard - Brook Hall, Bentley College, Waltham, MA 617-891-2000 11/17/1983 (formerly with Edison Papers Project) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Kathleen Oliver of Edison Laboratory - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Note from Kathleen Oliver April 4, 1961 - On Reference to Edison Laboratory (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lighting in Mgt. Text Books, 1912-1932 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - C.D. Wage, "Comparison of RATR and HIT Test Periods" (page 647 to Doctoral Presentation, Table L), 1924-1927 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - C.E. Snow - Time Values at Hawthorne 1925 - From Standards - (Note Coil Winding Time and Relay Time) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Snow's Notes on Earnings in Hawthorne Tests (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Instructions for Preparing Case for Psych 222, 1962 Univ. College, Rutgers (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Log. CES 1925 (Copies - Originals at Cornell) Hawthorne Illumination Tests (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Snow's Log Notes, 1924-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - C.E. Snow, Dept. 6329, Relay Assembly "E" Type Relays (Based on Earnings) - 1924-1925 Tests (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Charles E. Snow Log Notes & Charts from Illumination Tests at Hawthorne, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - C.E. Snow's Record of Production at Hawthorne 1924-1925 (with names of operators) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Original records
  - Data on Mr. W.H. Meese (Operating Mgr. at Hawthorne 1924) W.E. News Nov. 1927, p.12, 1924-1927 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - C.E. Snow 1924-1925 Report On: a) Increases in Production b) Limitation of Output (charts H-7, H-8) (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Various Snow Original Records of 1924-1925 Tests (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Snow Material From His Reports & Test Room Location Sketch 11/20/79, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Output 1924-1925 Tests Relay Assembly - E Type Relays (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Snow Charts - On Production Rate at Different Hours of the Day 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1924-1925 Output Charts (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Data (From Snow's Log) on "Buffer" on Lights at Hawthorne in 1925, 2/3/25, 2/4/25, 3/5/25 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - F.J. Schnaubelt and "Buffer" on lights at Hawthorne 2-3-1925, W.E. News Aug. 1927, p. 43, 1925-1927 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence with Chicago Weather Bureau, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - C.E. Snow Sunshine and "A" Relay Group, Dec. 8-31, 1924, Jan. 2, 1925 to Jan. 10, 1925, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1924-1925 Illumination Tests Summary (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Monthly Meteorological Summaries, Chicago, Illinois, 1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Envelope with documents
  - C.E. Snow - Lighting Survey During 1924-1925 Tests (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dennison Chart, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Original charts
  - Report on Dennison Tests 1925 (Copy Received from Leland Franke) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Dennison Mgt. Co. Illumination Study, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Chart
  - Dennison Mgt. Co. 1925 Napkin Cutting Dept. (Hawthorne Illumination Test) (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1926 Illum. Test Data (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Originals and copies of data
  - 1926 Test at Hawthorne by C.E. Snow (10-7-26) and Diagram of 1926-1927 Test Room, Snow 1926 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Search for John Sidebotham Tape Mills Study by Arthur A. Brainerd in 1926 for Dugald Jackson - Related to Hawthorne, 1957 Brainerd (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - John Sidebotham Tape Mills Test 1926 - by A.A. Brainerd (Thermo fax copy of report in T.A. Edison Files) (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Test Room (Light Test) at Hawthorne in 1926-1927 Tests (Box 3, Folder 36)
    Copies and originals
  - March 9, 1927 - Speed of Coil Winding Machines (Snow, 1927) at Hawthorne (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - "Light Test" & "Contrast Gang" of 1926-1927 Illumination Tests at Hawthorne - Copies of Snow's Original 68 pages (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Copies of original document
  - Snow "Light Test" Sheets 1927 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Illumination Tests at Hawthorne and With More Tests of 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 2-14-27 "Special Illumination Test Relay Assembly", 1927 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    Copy of original document
  - Notes and Manuscript Pages on "Moonlight" and "Light Bulb Test" 1964 at Hawthorne (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - On Mayo: Patricia Curtis Correspondence (Elton Mayo's daughter), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    Copies of original letters
  - Correspondence with Continental Mills (Phila) on Mayo Work, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Elton Mayo Letter G.A. Pennock, 2/9/31, (12 pages), 1931 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Letter to David W. Bailey (Howard) on Mayo Papers (M.L. Cooke Letter Feb. 1958) May 25, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Mayo - Brech Correspondence (Negative Photo Stat 12/2/43), 1943 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - List of Elton Mayo Newspaper Articles 1924-1929 (Summary of Data at Baker Library - Incomplete Files There) 1959 (Box 3, Folder 48)